<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shawnee Skogen</title>
    <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shawnee Skogen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 17:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shawnee-skogen.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021 Upcoming Summer Meetings</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-06-02-upcoming-summer-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-06-02-upcoming-summer-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Plans for the June and August meetings have been laid!
The June meeting will be held at Cahokia Mounds (Wikipedia, Official (bad SSL certificate)) on June 27th. We will meet up for lunch around noon and then head over to mounds at 2 PM.
The August meeting will be held August 22nd in Centralia, IL where we will get to enjoy the sights of the Centralia Balloon Fest.
Photo by Skubasteve834 - EN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Syttende Mai Meeting</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-05-16-syttende-mai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-05-16-syttende-mai/</guid>
      <description>We had an actual lodge meeting! Gratulerer med dagen! The companionship was delightful. The food was delicious. The kids loved playing together and making tasty Norwegian flags. Thanks to everyone who came it was it was so wonderful to see everyone in person again!
 Group Photo   Kids&#39; Edible Craft 
 Mike’s Story Time   Ron’s Awesome Troll Mask 
Check out all the photos in our 2021 Syttende Mai photo album.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Vaccinations Open to Any Illinois Resident Age 16 and up on April 12th</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-04-12-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-04-12-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>According to the State of Illinois Coronavirus Response any Illinois resident age 16 and up will be eligible to receive a COVID-19 vaccine on April 12th. For many of us this is a major milestone on the road to returning to normal and offers hope to being able to resume in-person lodge meetings. Between vaccines being available and the weather allowing us to meet outdoors we hope to see familiar faces in-person soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Syttende Mai Meeting May 16, 2021</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-03-28-syttende-mai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-03-28-syttende-mai/</guid>
      <description>Every year Norwegians celebrate Constitution Day often referred to just as &amp;ldquo;syttende mai&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Seventeenth May&amp;rdquo;). In Norway the day will feature children&amp;rsquo;s parades all over the country, memorials to those fallen in wars, and russ. Men, women, and children often wear traditional outfits called bunad or wear red, white and blue ribbons and carry flags. Around the world Norwegian communities celebrate with traditional foods and in some cases putting on their own parades and festivities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Lefse Making Meeting November 15, 2020</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2020-11-15-lefse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 21:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2020-11-15-lefse/</guid>
      <description>Every year we make lefse,
 Lefse is a traditional soft Norwegian flatbread. It is made with potatoes (often, but not always), flour, butter, and milk or cream. It is cooked on a large, flat griddle. Special tools are used to prepare lefse, including long wooden turning sticks and special rolling pins with deep grooves.
 It&amp;rsquo;s almost like a flour tortilla but softer and tastier and Norwegian!
Consider joining our lodge so you can learn to make lefse and all sorts of other Scandinavian art, food, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
