<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shawnee Skogen</title>
    <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shawnee Skogen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 14:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shawnee-skogen.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Syttende Mai Recap</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2023-05-23-syttende-mai-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2023-05-23-syttende-mai-recap/</guid>
      <description>We were blessed with good weather for Syttende Mai and got to enjoy the company of many members and neighbors to our hosts,
As always seems to be the case, the potluck featured many delicious food options,
There was lounging, swimming, and canoeing enjoyed by many! Thanks to this beautiful lake front,
See the &amp;lsquo;23 Syttende Mai photo album to peruse the photos from the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syttende Mai Invitation</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2023-04-27-syttende-mai-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2023-04-27-syttende-mai-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Every year Norwegians celebrate Constitution Day, often referred to just as &amp;ldquo;syttende mai&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Seventeenth May&amp;rdquo;). In Norway the day will feature children&amp;rsquo;s parades all over the country, memorials to those fallen in wars, and russ. Men, women, and children often wear traditional outfits called bunad or wear red, white and blue ribbons and carry flags. Around the world Norwegian communities celebrate with traditional foods and in some cases putting on their own parades and festivities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule Updated for 2023</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2023-03-05-updated-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 14:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2023-03-05-updated-schedule/</guid>
      <description>The schedule has been updated for 2023 with what we know so far in terms of programming. The next meeting will feature a program on Thor Heyerdahl presented by Ron Naversen. It will be held at St. Nicholas Brewing Company (12 S Oak St, Du Quoin, IL 62832) like February&amp;rsquo;s meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Lefse &amp; Julebord Meeting Recaps</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-11-lefse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-11-lefse/</guid>
      <description>Well, apparently the lefse meeting recap is a hurdle for me because here I am writing it, months late, and I go to copy the one from last year as a starting point and to discover it opened with,
 Gosh! I forgot to post after we made lefse last month!
 Since the lefse meeting in November we&amp;rsquo;ve also the julebord meeting in December and a January Zoom meeting. Tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;re meeting in Du Quoin at the usual 2 PM and it will be nice to see folks in person again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 August Meeting in Centralia</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-08-centralia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 18:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-08-centralia/</guid>
      <description>For our August meeting Mike and Jeannell Charman graciously hosted us at their home in Centralia. Their property sits on Centralia Reservoir where hot air balloons from the Centralia Balloonfest will glide over the water’s surface.
We had a “fotball kamp” for a chance to win bracelets for entry into the balloonfest. Jess was the first to make it into the goal but Chuck didn’t let her enjoy her victory long as he followed her with his own goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 District 5 Convention</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-06-20-district-5-convention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-06-20-district-5-convention/</guid>
      <description>Wendy, Bill, and Nathan attended the 2022 District 5 Convention that took place June 15-19 in Middleton, WI. We were there to represent our lodge by voting on any proposals and resolutions, to elect the district officers for the next biennium, and to elect our international delegates for the 2022 International Convention.
Coming out of the convention all three were also elected as district officers:
 Wendy is serving as the District 5 Vice President.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metropolitan Orchestra of St. Louis: Pop-Up Concert</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-06-13-mosl-pop-up-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 16:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-06-13-mosl-pop-up-concert/</guid>
      <description>One of our lodge members, Ann Dolan, is a flutist in The Metropolitan Orchestra of St. Louis so we visited one of their summer &amp;ldquo;Pop-Up Concerts&amp;rdquo; on June 5th. It was an absolutely blissful evening and very entertaining to listen to a concert from a few feet away. The theme of the concert was &amp;ldquo;Around the World&amp;rdquo; and one of the stops included a stop in Norway with a piece by Norwegian composer, Johannes Hanssen, called &amp;ldquo;Valdres March&amp;rdquo;; here is the performance,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 May Meeting Recap: Syttende Mai</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-06-13-syttende-mai-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-06-13-syttende-mai-recap/</guid>
      <description>Gratulerer med dagen! The weather gave us a reprieve and we were able to enjoy a wonderful picnic with many of our lodge members. In Norwegian tradition, hot dogs were grilled and we attempted to serve ice cream. There was a wonderful variety of dishes, some of which were made possible thanks to the Charmans&#39; RV kitchenette. We enjoyed seeing several lodge members we have not seen in a while!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Påskestradisjoner</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-04-10-pasketradisjoner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-04-10-pasketradisjoner/</guid>
      <description>Påskestradisjoner just means &amp;ldquo;Easter Traditions&amp;rdquo;. Even when the same holidays are celebrated in different cultures there are often little, interesting differences. Easter has its roots as a spring festival and from Christianity with the resurrection of Jesus so there are many similarities between Norway and the United States but there are also differences. We do live in a very connected world and traditions tend to spread whether that be organically or due to corporate marketing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailing Lists Transitioning to Forum</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-03-13-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-03-13-music/</guid>
      <description>Shawnee Skogen Members,
In an ironic twist, after finally just bulk adding everyone to the mailing lists, I have discovered a major technical hurdle which means I&amp;rsquo;ll have to transition to an alternate solution for online discussion. Therefore, I have removed the link to the &amp;ldquo;Mailing Lists&amp;rdquo; on the sidebar and replaced it with a link to our &amp;ldquo;Forum&amp;rdquo; instead. I&amp;rsquo;ll be testing the forum server over the coming days/weeks to avoid repeating my mistake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 January Meeting Recap: Cultural Skills: Music</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-01-16-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2022-01-16-music/</guid>
      <description>Part of Sons of Norway is a pin system for various activities primarily falling under two programs: Cultural Skills and Sports Medals. Today&amp;rsquo;s meeting was an experiment to see if were could complete &amp;ldquo;Music and Musicians of Norway Part 1: Folk Music: Roots of Norwegian Music&amp;rdquo; together over Zoom. Wendy organized a program around its activity sheet consisting of a playlist, group discussion, and support from our musically inclined members: Ann, Nancy, and Todd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Lefse Meeting Recap</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-11-21-lefse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-11-21-lefse/</guid>
      <description>Gosh! I forgot to post after we made lefse last month! Well, everyone had fun and got to make lefse. Ron also awarded a couple sports medals; gratulerer! Some beverages were enjoyed and some lefse were &amp;ldquo;quality controlled&amp;rdquo;, yum. Checkout the photos in the shared album.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God Jul Til Alle</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-12-12-julebord/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-12-12-julebord/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday, December 12th, we had our annual Julebord potluck. We got to enjoy many tasty dishes and desserts, check out the 2021 Julebord photo album to see some of them. We enjoyed some discussion, some shared traditions, and, completely unrelated, some VR gaming.
We wish everyone a merry Christmas and happy holidays!
Please enjoy this youth choir&amp;rsquo;s julesangen, &amp;ldquo;God Jul Til Alle&amp;rdquo;,
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lefse making November 21st and Julebord December 12!</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-11-14-upcoming-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 14:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-11-14-upcoming-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Our annual lefse meeting is next week, the 21st, starting around noon at Wendy &amp;amp; Bill&amp;rsquo;s home. If you&amp;rsquo;re interesting in making a batch of lefse dough please let Wendy know; we&amp;rsquo;ll need a few batches made. We&amp;rsquo;ll have at least two stations setup, maybe three. Kids and adults can participate and there&amp;rsquo;s a deck, a yard, etc. for folks to enjoy. Lefse can be frozen and used year-round. It can be enjoyed by your family or sold as a fundraiser for the lodge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 October Meeting Canceled: Giant City State Park</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-10-17-giant-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-10-17-giant-city/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately, the October meeting has been canceled due to low RSVPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 September Meeting Recap: Giant City State Park</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-09-26-giant-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-09-26-giant-city/</guid>
      <description>For September we met at Giant City State Park and the weather was absolutely sublime. After taking care of the formal lodge meeting we continued on with a presentation from Wendy about the state and relations of the royal families of Europe.
After the presentation we played a game of Kubb which purports to be an ancient Viking game. It was introduced to our lodge via Nordic Fest which sometimes hosts a Kubb tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 June Meeting Recap: Cahokia Mounds</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-06-27-cahokia-mounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-06-27-cahokia-mounds/</guid>
      <description>Eleven of us met up at the Old Herald Brewery &amp;amp; Distillery for lunch before heading over to the Cahokia Mounds (Wikipedia). There we were joined by a few more members bringing us to sixteen in total. It was wonderful to see everyone but in particular a couple members we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen in a long time as well as several newer members for which this was their first or second in-person meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Upcoming Summer Meetings</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-06-02-upcoming-summer-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-06-02-upcoming-summer-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Plans for the June and August meetings have been laid!
The June meeting will be held at Cahokia Mounds (Wikipedia, Official) on June 27th. We will meet up for lunch around noon and then head over to mounds at 2 PM.
The August meeting will be held August 22nd in Centralia, IL where we will get to enjoy the sights of the Centralia Balloon Fest.
Photo by Skubasteve834 - EN.Wikipedia, CC BY-SA 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 May Meeting Recap: Syttende Mai</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-05-16-syttende-mai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-05-16-syttende-mai/</guid>
      <description>We had an actual lodge meeting! Gratulerer med dagen! The companionship was delightful. The food was delicious. The kids loved playing together and making tasty Norwegian flags. Thanks to everyone who came it was it was so wonderful to see everyone in person again!
 Group Photo   Kids&#39; Edible Craft 
 Mike’s Story Time   Ron’s Awesome Troll Mask 
Check out all the photos in our 2021 Syttende Mai photo album.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Vaccinations Open to Any Illinois Resident Age 16 and up on April 12th</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-04-12-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-04-12-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>According to the State of Illinois Coronavirus Response any Illinois resident age 16 and up will be eligible to receive a COVID-19 vaccine on April 12th. For many of us this is a major milestone on the road to returning to normal and offers hope to being able to resume in-person lodge meetings. Between vaccines being available and the weather allowing us to meet outdoors we hope to see familiar faces in-person soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Syttende Mai Meeting May 16, 2021</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-03-28-syttende-mai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2021-03-28-syttende-mai/</guid>
      <description>Every year Norwegians celebrate Constitution Day often referred to just as &amp;ldquo;syttende mai&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Seventeenth May&amp;rdquo;). In Norway the day will feature children&amp;rsquo;s parades all over the country, memorials to those fallen in wars, and russ. Men, women, and children often wear traditional outfits called bunad or wear red, white and blue ribbons and carry flags. Around the world Norwegian communities celebrate with traditional foods and in some cases putting on their own parades and festivities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Lefse Making Meeting November 15, 2020</title>
      <link>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2020-11-15-lefse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 21:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawnee-skogen.com/p/2020-11-15-lefse/</guid>
      <description>Every year we make lefse,
 Lefse is a traditional soft Norwegian flatbread. It is made with potatoes (often, but not always), flour, butter, and milk or cream. It is cooked on a large, flat griddle. Special tools are used to prepare lefse, including long wooden turning sticks and special rolling pins with deep grooves.
 It&amp;rsquo;s almost like a flour tortilla but softer and tastier and Norwegian!
Consider joining our lodge so you can learn to make lefse and all sorts of other Scandinavian art, food, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
